<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on DATA621 BLOGS</title>
    <link>https://aaitelmouden.github.io/blog.github.io/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on DATA621 BLOGS</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>© Abdellah</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 13 May 2021 10:56:08 -0600</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://aaitelmouden.github.io/blog.github.io/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Blog V: K-Nearest Neighbor Regression Example in R </title>
      <link>https://aaitelmouden.github.io/blog.github.io/posts/blog5/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 May 2021 10:56:08 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://aaitelmouden.github.io/blog.github.io/posts/blog5/</guid>
      <description>Data Scientist often have multivariate data, and want to make predictions or groupings based on certain aspects of their data. In this algorithm, k is a constant defined by user and nearest neighbors distances vector is calculated by using it.
The &amp;lsquo;caret&amp;rsquo; package provides &amp;lsquo;knnreg&amp;rsquo; function to apply KNN for regression problems. In this article, we&amp;rsquo;ll briefly learn how to fit and predict regression data by using &amp;lsquo;knnreg&amp;rsquo; function in R.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Blog IV:  Why not Linear Regression for Classification</title>
      <link>https://aaitelmouden.github.io/blog.github.io/posts/blog4/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Apr 2021 10:56:08 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://aaitelmouden.github.io/blog.github.io/posts/blog4/</guid>
      <description>Linear regression model assumes that the response variable Y is quantitative. But in many situations, the response variable is instead qualitative. But in many situations, the response variable is instead qualitative. Predicting a qualitative response for an observation can be referred to as classifying that observation, since it involves assigning the observation to a category, or class. the most widely-used classiﬁers: logistic regression, linear discriminant analysis, and K-nearest neighbors.
Why Not Linear Regression?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Blog III: Choosing the Correct Regression Model</title>
      <link>https://aaitelmouden.github.io/blog.github.io/posts/blog3/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Apr 2021 10:56:08 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://aaitelmouden.github.io/blog.github.io/posts/blog3/</guid>
      <description>The process of deciding which independent variables to include and remove from a regression equation is known as model specification. How do you choose the most appropriate regression model? The world is complex, and attempting to understand it with a limited sample size is futile. In this article, I&amp;rsquo;ll show you how to choose the right one.
When a researcher needs to mathematically describe the relationship between independent variables and the dependent variable, model selection is often needed.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title> Blog II: Simple Linear Regression</title>
      <link>https://aaitelmouden.github.io/blog.github.io/posts/blog2/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Apr 2021 10:56:08 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://aaitelmouden.github.io/blog.github.io/posts/blog2/</guid>
      <description>Formula and basics The mathematical formula of the linear regression can be written as $$y = b0 + b1*x + e$$, where:
 b0 and b1 are known as the regression beta coefficients or parameters:  b0 is the intercept of the regression line; that is the predicted value when x = 0. b1 is the slope of the regression line.   e is the error term (also known as the residual errors), the part of y that can be explained by the regression model  Linear Regression Using R For this example we will use the Boston data set from the MASS library, which records medv (median house value) for 506 neighborhoods around Boston.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Blog I : Education and Life Expectancy</title>
      <link>https://aaitelmouden.github.io/blog.github.io/posts/blog1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Mar 2021 10:56:08 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://aaitelmouden.github.io/blog.github.io/posts/blog1/</guid>
      <description>Significant reductions in mortality are reflected in strong increases in life expectancy particularly in industrialized countries. Previous studies relate these improvements primarily to medical innovations and advances in health-related behaviors. Mostly ignored, however, is the question to what extent the gains in life expectancy are related to increasing education levels. In this article we will try to answer the question about the relation between the mean of Life Expectancy in age and the number of years of education.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>